OFFICE OF COMMUNICATIONS AND MARKETING RECORDS (UA390) 1981-2005
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Office of Communications and Marketing Records 1981-2005
nam_ua390
5.0
Office of Communications and Marketing (University at Albany)
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Office of Communications and Marketing Records contain video footage of winter and spring commencement ceremonies at the University at Albany between 1981-2005.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
The M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives received these videos from the Office of Communications and Marketing.
Biographical Sketch
Founded in 1844 as the New York State Normal School, the University at Albany held its first commencement ceremony in 1845. The first graduating class of the Normal School consisted of 34 graduates; 29 men and 5 women. Currently the University at Albany holds two commencements during the year, one in May and the other in the December, with more than 3,000 students receiving degrees annually.
Scope and Content Information
While the Office of Communications and Marketing annually films many other campus events, the commencement videos are the first to be included in this finding aid. Therefore the records primarily include VHS, Mini-DV and DVD footage of May undergraduate and graduate commencement ceremonies and a smaller amount of footage from the joint winter commencement in December. Frequently there are multiple videos for the same ceremony, including footage taken from different angles. Some videos feature departmental commencements or other annual events, such as “Torch Night,” which is held the day before graduation and inducts graduates into the Alumni Association.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically. There are no series.
Subject and Genre Headings
State University of New York at Albany; State University of New York at Albany--Office of Communications and Marketing; Commencement ceremonies--New York (State)--Albany; Education, Higher--New York (State); VHS (TM); DVDs; Videocassettes
Container List
- Commencement - Back-up Tape, 1981 May 24 (Video-tape 1)
- Commencement, 1982 May 23 (Video-tape 2)
- Commencement - Lighting Test at the Lectern on the Speakers Platform, 1984 (Video-tape 3)
- Commencement, 1985; 4 duplicate copies (Video-tape 4-7)
- Commencement - Graduate Ceremony - Podium Camera and Master Audio - Tape #1, 1985 May 15 (Video-tape 8)
- Commencement - Graduate Ceremony - Podium Camera and Master Audio - Tape #2, 1985 May 15 (Video-tape 9)
- SUNY Albany Commencement, 1985 May 19 (Video-tape 10)
- SUNY Albany Commencement, 1986 May 18; 3 duplicate copies (Video-tape 11-13)
- 143rd Commencement, 1987 May 17; 4 duplicate copies (Video-tape 14-17)
- 143rd Commencement - Chemistry Doctorates - Dr. Eric Block - Chemistry Department, 1987 May 17 (Video-tape 18-21)
- 143rd Commencement - Edited Master, 1987 May 17 (Video-tape 22)
- SUNYA Commencement, 1987 May 17; 7 duplicate copies (Video-tape 23-29)
- Commencement - Torch Night, 1988 May 14; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 30-31)
- 144th Commencement - Undergraduate Ceremony, 1988 May 15; 3 duplicate copies (Video-tape 32-34)
- 144th SUNYA Commencement, 1988 May 15; 10 duplicate copies (Video-tape 35-44)
- Commencement - Undergraduate Ceremony - Podium Camera, 1988 May 15 (Video-tape 45)
- Commencement - Undergraduate Ceremony – Platform Camera, 1988 May 15 (Video-tape 46)
- Commencement - Undergraduate Ceremony – Roving Camera (LEN), 1988 May 15 (Video-tape 47)
- Commencement - Undergraduate and Graduate Ceremony – Roving Camera (BILL), 1988 May 15 (Video-tape 48)
- Commencement, 1991 May 26; 6 duplicate copies (Video-tape 49-54)
- 147th Commencement, 1991 May 26; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 55-56)
- 147th Commencement - Center Stage Camera, 1991 May 26; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 57-58)
- 147th Commencement - Stage Left Camera, 1991 May 26 (Video-tape 52)
- 147th Commencement - Stage Right Camera, 1991 May 26; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 60-61)
- 148th Commencement, 1992; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 62-63)
- 149th Commencement, 1993 May 16; 4 duplicate copies (Video-tape 64-67)
- 150th Commencement, 1994 May 15; 5 duplicate copies (Video-tape 68-72)
- Fountain Day and Graduation - Tape #1, 1994 (Video-tape 73)
- Fountain Day and Graduation - Tape #2, 1994 (Video-tape 74)
- 151st Commencement - Undergraduate Ceremony - Edited Master, 1995 (Video-tape 75)
- 151st Commencement - Graduate, 1995; 3 duplicate copies (Video-tape 76-78)
- Graduate UA Ceremony, 1995; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 79-80)
- Undergraduate UA Ceremony, 1995; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 81-82)
- Graduation – Suits Master – Stage Right – Undergraduate, 1996 (Video-tape 83)
- Graduation – Suits Master – Stage Right – Undergraduate @ Pepsi Arena, 1996 (Video-tape 84)
- Graduation Stage Left – Undergraduate @ Pepsi Arena, 1996 (Video-tape 85)
- Graduation – Stage Left – Graduate Ceremony @ RAAC, 1996 (Video-tape 86)
- Graduation Ceremony @ RAAC – Stage Right – Audio on Separate VHS, 1996; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 87-88)
- Graduation – Stage Right - @ RAAC Tape #1, 1996 (Video-tape 89)
- Graduation – Stage Right - @ RAAC Tape #2, 1996 (Video-tape 90)
- 152nd Commencement - SUNYA- Undergraduate Ceremony, 1996 May 19; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 91-92)
- 152nd Commencement - SUNYA - Graduate - Doctors, Masters, 1996 May 19; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 93-94)
- Graduation – Graduate – RAAC – Final Edited Master, 1997 (Video-tape 95)
- Graduation – Graduate – RAAC – Master, Stage Right – Shot close from floor, 1997 (Video-tape 96)
- Graduation – Undergraduate (Knick) - Tape #1 – Stage Right, 1997 (Video-tape 97)
- University at Albany Commencement– Graduate Ceremony, 1997; 7 duplicate copies (Video-tape 98-104)
- University at Albany Commencement – Undergraduate Ceremony, 1997; 4 duplicate copies (Video-tape 105-108)
- Commencement University at Albany Graduation – Undergraduate, 1998; 5 duplicate copies (Video-tape 109-113)
- Commencement University at Albany – Graduate, 1998; 3 duplicate copies (Video-tape 114-116)
- Commencement - Senior Class Video, 1998 (Video-tape 117)
- Commencement State University of New York at Albany, 1998 December 11 (Video-tape 118)
- Commencement Ceremony – Graduate, 1999; 7 duplicate copies (Video-tape 119-125)
- Commencement Ceremony – Undergraduate, 1999; 6 duplicate copies (Video-tape 126-131)
- Pre Commencement Ceremony Picture - Master Copy, 1999 (Video-tape 132)
- Commencement Clip - Ch. 13 News 11:00pm, 1999 May 23 (Video-tape 133)
- Graduation @RAAC – Master – Graduate Ceremony – Stage Left - Tape #1, 1999 May 23 (Video-tape 134)
- Graduation @RAAC – Master – Graduate Ceremony – Stage Left - Tape #2, 1999 May 23 (Video-tape 135)
- Commencement – Stage Right – Graduate Ceremony Part 1, 2000 (Video-tape 136)
- Commencement – Stage Right – Graduate Ceremony Part 2, 2000 (Video-tape 137)
- University at Albany – Stage Right- Master Copy– Graduate Ceremony -Tape #1, 2000 (Video-tape 138)
- University at Albany – Stage Right- Master Copy – Graduate Ceremony - Tape #2, 2000 (Video-tape 139)
- University at Albany Graduation – Undergraduate, 2000 (Video-tape 140)
- University at Albany Graduation – Graduate, 2000 (Video-tape 141)
- Graduation – University at Albany – Graduate Ceremony, 2000; 3 duplicate copies (Video-tape 142-144)
- University at Albany – Graduation – Undergraduate Ceremony, 2000; 10 duplicate copies (Video-tape 145-154)
- University at Albany Graduation – Stage Left at the RAAC – Graduate Ceremony - Tape #1, 2000 May 21 (Video-tape 155)
- University at Albany – Graduation– Undergraduate at Pepsi Arena (Master Copy), 2000 May 21 (Video-tape 156)
- University at Albany Graduation – Stage Left at the RAAC – Graduate Ceremony - Tape #2, 2000 May 21 (Video-tape 157)
- Graduation – University at Albany – Master – Graduate Ceremony, 2000 May 21 (Video-tape 158)
- Graduation – University at Albany – Graduate Ceremony – COPY, 2000 May 21 (Video-tape 159)
- University at Albany – Graduation 2000 – Graduate Ceremony – RAAC, 2000 May 21 (Video-tape 160)
- Undergraduate Ceremony – Raw Footage, 2001 (Video-tape 161)
- Graduate Ceremony – Master - Raw Material, 2001 (Video-tape 162)
- Undergraduate Ceremony - Dub from Dig8 Original, 2001 (Video-tape 163)
- University at Albany – Undergraduate Ceremony – Master, 2001 (Video-tape 164)
- University at Albany – Undergraduate Ceremony Duplication, 2001 (Video-tape 165)
- Graduate Ceremony – Wayne Tape #2, 2002 (Video-tape 166)
- Commencement - University at Albany - Graduate - Spring, 2002 (Video-tape 167)
- Commencement - Undergraduate, 2002 May 19; 2 duplicate copies (Video-tape 168-169)
- Commencement - University at Albany, 2002 December 08; 6 duplicate copies (Video-tape 170-175)
- Graduate Ceremony - Master, 2004 May 15 (Video-tape 176)
- Graduate Ceremony, 2004 May 15 (Video-tape 177)
- Undergraduate Ceremony, 2004 May 16; 6 duplicate copies (Video-tape 178-183)
- SUNY A CAM - Tape #1 (Tapes), 2004 December (Video-tape 184)
- SUNY A CAM - Tape #2 (Tapes), 2004 December (Video-tape 185)
- SUNY A CAM - Tape #3 (Tapes), 2004 December (Video-tape 186)
- SUNY B CAM - Tape #1 (Tapes), 2004 December (Video-tape 187)
- SUNY B CAM - Tape #2 (Tapes), 2004 December (Video-tape 188)
- Commencement, 2004 December 12; 4 duplicate copies (Video-tape 189-192)
- SUNY A CAM - Tape #1 (Tapes), 2005 May 14 (Video-tape 193)
- SUNY A CAM - Tape #2 (Tapes), 2005 May 14 (Video-tape 194)
- SUNY A CAM - Tape #3 (Tapes), 2005 May 14 (Video-tape 195)
- Commencement - Graduate, 2005 May 14; 4 duplicate copies (Video-tape 196-199)
- SUNY 1, 2005 May 14 (Video-tape 200)
- SUNY B CAM - Tape #1 (Tapes), 2005 May 15 (Video-tape 201)
- SUNY B CAM - Tape #2 (Tapes), 2005 May 15 (Video-tape 202)
- SUNY B CAM - Tape #3 (Tapes), 2005 May 15 (Video-tape 203)
- Commencement - Undergraduate, 2005 May 15 (Video-tape 204)
- SUNY 2, 2005 May 15 (Video-tape 205)
- Loop Tape - Pre Ceremony, Undated (Video-tape 206)
- Graduate Ceremony – University at Albany – Master DV- Spring, 2002 (Dvd 1)
- Undergraduate Stage Right - Wayne, 2005 May (Dvd 2)
- Graduation - Wayne Tape #2 - Extra Footage, 2002 December (Dvd 3)
- Graduate Ceremony - Tape #1, 2002 December (Dvd 4)
- Graduate Ceremony - Tape #2, 2002 December (Dvd 5)
- Graduation - Stage left - Tape #2, 2002 December (Dvd 6)
- Commencement, 2003 December; 4 duplicate copies (Dvd 7-10)
- Ceremonies, 2005 May (Dvd 11)
- Undergraduate SONY Version, 2001 (Mini-dv 1)
- Commencement, 2002 (Mini-dv 2)
- Undergraduate Ceremony, 2003 (Mini-dv 3)
- Graduate Ceremony, 2003 (Mini-dv 4)
- University at Albany - Graduate Ceremony, 2004 May 15 (Mini-dv 5)
- University at Albany - Undergraduate Ceremony, 2004 May 15 (Mini-dv 6)